Tobias Pristupin

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER St. Louis, MO

□ +1 954-371-7815

p.tobias@wustl.edu | * www.pristu.dev

Summary_

Hi, I'm Tobias. I am a self taught programmer from Argentina with 6 years of experience. I have experience in mobile development, compiler design, full stack web development, embedded systems, and competitive programming. More information about my projects can be found on my website.

Education

Washington University in St. Louis - Expected Graduation May 2024

St. Louis, MO

COMPUTER SCIENCE + MATHEMATICS MAJOR

Aug. 2020 - 2024

- Attending on a full scholarship as a John B. Ervin Scholar. GPA 3.97/4. Relevant coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms (A+), Discrete Mathematics (A+ and now working as a Teacher Assistant), Linear Algebra (A+), Full Stack Web Development CSE 330 (A+).
- Currently working as a Research Assistant in the Parallel Computing Technology Group. My research is focused on the mathematical analysis of parallel scheduling algorithms.

Work Experience & Projects

Facebook Menlo Park, CA

University Software Engineering Intern

Jun. 2021 - Aug. 2021

- Designed and implemented community building Android app that scales to 100k+ users. Used Firebase DB and Cloud Storage, Google NLP REST API, RxJava, Retrofit, Unit Testing.
- Shadowed full time engineers to learn development workflow. Learned Phabricator, best practices for code review and

Lox Programming Language Research Study

Washington University in St.

Louis

RESEARCHER & DEVELOPER

2020-21

- Developed an interpreter from scratch in C++ for the Lox Programming language as a personal project.
- Created a bytecode compiler and a stack based virtual machine for Lox, also in C++, as an independent research project under the supervision of Professor J. Shidal.
- Implemented my own garbage collection algorithms based on multiple research papers. Benchmarked the algorithms and wrote a research paper summarizing my findings.

Smart RC Car GitHub

DEVELOPER - PERSONAL PROJECT

2021

• Retrofitted old RC car with a Raspberry Pi to control acceleration and steering. RPI acts as a web server that can be controlled via wifi through a phone app.

Minimal Running GitHub

DEVELOPER - PERSONAL PROJECT

2018-19

 Published Android application with 100+ downloads. Allows user to log their running activities and view statistics on their progress. Users can use an account to store their data online.

Volunteering

sErvin

Washington University in St.

Louis

CO-PRESIDENT Restarted a community service group within John B. Ervin scholars that had been inactive for 5 years.

Jan. 2019 - Present

Directed community outreach events with UnhousedSTL for a group of 30 scholars

Skills

Experience with

C++, Java, Python, JS, PHP, HTML/CSS, SQL, MongoDB, Node.js, React, Flask, Apache, Linux, Android Dev, Flutter, Firebase, AWS, RxJava, Arduino, Mathematica, Bilingual (Spanish and English)